<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-17T17:46:32+00:00</updated><id>https://ombhilare999.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Graduate teaching assistant info</title><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/TA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graduate teaching assistant info"/><published>2022-07-25T17:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-25T17:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/TA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/TA/"><![CDATA[<p>As you are all aware, these TA positions are quite competitive, but if you apply early, you will have a far better chance of getting one. This page contains information on locating a suitable course for TA and a sample email template to send to professors.</p> <h2 id="when-to-apply">When to apply:</h2> <p>After professors request TA, the courses will typically appear on some TA job platform (<a href="http://unit1.hrandequity.utoronto.ca/">CUPE LOCAL 3902</a>). This usually occurs in late July at the University of Toronto. I believe that the longer you wait for this official position to come up, the lower your chances get.</p> <p>As a result, the best method to apply for TA is to keep an eye out for Courses announcements for undergraduate students in your/other departments. That course catalog can be found on the undergraduate page of the department. In my situation, I discovered the following <a href="https://app.powerbi.com/groups/me/reports/affc0c88-646f-452b-a5fe-645c73a25938/ReportSection?ctid=78aac226-2f03-4b4d-9037-b46d56c55210&amp;openReportSource=ReportInvitation&amp;experience=power-bi">link</a> from the UofT’s ECE undergraduate page, where I could view the timetable of UofT Professors.</p> <h2 id="suitable-course">Suitable course:</h2> <p>You can select the appropriate course from the catalog based on your interests. Consider taking a class if you excelled in related undergraduate coursework and have a lot of project experience.</p> <p>I chose the following course because I did well in a similar undergraduate course and had numerous projects to show the instructor.</p> <table class="center"> <tr> <th>Session Name</th> <th>Dept</th> <th>Full Title</th> <th>Section</th> <th>Start Date</th> </tr> <tr> <td>Fall 2023</td> <td>ECE</td> <td>ECE241H1F: DIGITAL SYSTEMS</td> <td>LEC 0101</td> <td>2023-09-07</td> </tr> </table> <p><br/></p> <p>Also, before sending a cold email, check the course’s laboratories to determine what software and experiments they are conducting. I reviewed ECE241’s syllabus (l<a href="https://www.ece.utoronto.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CourseInfo_ECE241_2019.pdf">ink</a>) and noticed that they use Intel’s Quartus prime to simulate digital circuits in FPGA laboratories. I had done many projects related to this, which I mentioned in my cold email, which you can find below.</p> <h2 id="application-procedure">Application Procedure:</h2> <p>Apply on the Electrical and Computer Engineering on-line TA Database. Instructions and link are posted on the ECE TA web page: <a href="https://www.ece.utoronto.ca/faculty/career-opportunities/">https://www.ece.utoronto.ca/faculty/career-opportunities/</a> or directly at: <a href="https://eceta.ece.toronto.edu/">https://eceta.ece.toronto.edu/</a>.</p> <h2 id="sample-mail">Sample Mail:</h2> <p><em>Subject:</em> Request to be a Teaching Assistant for ECE241H1F: Digital Systems in Fall 2023</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Hi &lt;Prof&gt;,

I hope you are doing well. I had come across the following link [here](https://app.powerbi.com/groups/me/reports/affc0c88-646f-452b-a5fe-645c73a25938/ReportSection?ctid=78aac226-2f03-4b4d-9037-b46d56c55210&amp;openReportSource=ReportInvitation&amp;experience=power-bi) and saw that you were the course Instructor for the “ECE241 Digital System” course for ECE undergraduate students.

| Session Name | Dept | Full Title | Section | Start Date |
| ---------- |:------:| :-----:| :-----:| :-----:|
| Fall 2023 | ECE | ECE241H1F: DIGITAL SYSTEMS | LEC 0101 | 2023-09-07 |

I'm writing to inquire about the possibility of serving as a Teaching Assistant (TA) for the course for the fall semester of 2023. I believe my expertise is well-aligned with the course material.

**What makes me suitable?**

- I earned a score of 10/10 in courses such as "Digital Combinational Circuits" and "Digital Sequential Lab" [[Transcript]](http://omkarbhilare.me/pdf/Omkar_Bhilare_Transcripts.pdf) during my undergraduate studies.
- I observed that in the previous edition of the lab course, we implemented circuits on FPGAs and used Intel's Quartus toolchain. During my many projects and courses, I have used Intel, Xilinx, and Open-source FPGA toolchains extensively.
    - In Summer@EPFL project, we were doing Mixed mode simulation as the dynamatic contained both Verilog and VHDL. [**Done on Quartus, also used Vivado for power, area estimations**.]
    - Undergraduate thesis: Accelerated Deepfake detection on Versal FPGA [[Hackster.io](https://www.hackster.io/thematrix/deepfakes-c-l-i-on-vck5000-f04ca2#toc-2-4-evaluation-12)] [**Vivado, Vitis AI**]
    - Ping Pong game on ICE40Hx FPGA (Beaglewire) [[Github](https://github.com/BeagleWire/BeagleWire/tree/master/examples/vga_pong)] [**Yosys**]
    - 8-Bit-ALU-Implementation-on-CYCLONE-2 [[Github Link](https://github.com/ombhilare999/8-Bit-ALU-implementation-on-CYCLONE-2)] [**Quartus, iVerilog, GTKWAVE**]
    - Seven segments [[Github](https://github.com/ombhilare999/Seven-Segment-with-Tang-Primer-FPGA)] and VGA [[Github](https://github.com/ombhilare999/vga-interface-with-TANG-PRIMER-FPGA)] Driver for Tang Primer FPGA [**TD IDE**]
- I was also a joint-general secretary of a robotics club in my undergraduate college, where I mentored and taught many junior students on topics related to FPGAs, Computer architecture, and digital design. I would love to use that experience here as well.

I am eager to contribute to the undergraduate learning experience while expanding my own knowledge of the subject. Please let me know what you think. Have a nice day!

Regards,

Omkar Bhilare
</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="compensation">Compensation:</h2> <p>As of 01/01/2023, the hourly rate for TAs in undergraduate courses at the University of Toronto was $47.64. For a semester, you will receive approximately $3,500. Therefore, you will typically need to devote approximately 75 hours per semester. (This may vary from department to department)</p> <p>In some colleges, TA students are also eligible for tuition fee waivers; you can clarify this with your department administrators.</p> <h2 id="side-note">Side Note:</h2> <p>The course that I applied for was taken by my master’s thesis adviser, however, because some courses have multiple instructors, they will need to inform other professors as well. My professor responded positively as follows:</p> <blockquote> <p>Great — I’m meeting with the ECE241 instructors Thursday so I’ll let them know we should hire you as a TA.</p> </blockquote> <p>Now I will apply formally as well when the course TA position will be online near July end.</p> <p>I hope this was helpful in your search; please let me know if you have any further queries.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="informative"/><category term="informative"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This page contains information on locating a suitable course for TA and a sample email template to send to professors.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer EPFL Offer from LAP LAB</title><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/epfl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer EPFL Offer from LAP LAB"/><published>2022-01-25T17:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-25T17:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/epfl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2022/epfl/"><![CDATA[<p align="center"> <img width="602" height="606" src="/assets/img/2022-03-18-15-36-58.png"/> </p> <h2 id="about-summer-epfl-program">About Summer EPFL Program:</h2> <p>The School of Computer and Communication Sciences of the École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL) offers summer fellowships to international students. Participants get the chance to learn new skills and to gain hands-on experience in their chosen field while collaborating with leading senior scientists.</p> <p>Fellowship recipients will participate into the life of a research unit, typically to help solve problems which are usually part of major research efforts. Often, this will lead to performing challenging programming or design tasks to prove new concepts. Accepted students will receive a living allowance of CHF 1,600.- per month (pro rata to the actual duration) and a refund of travelling costs (2nd class train ticket or low-cost/economy airfare).</p> <h2 id="application-period--process">Application Period &amp; Process:</h2> <p align="center"> <img width="440" height="420" src="/assets/img/2022-03-18-15-42-09.png"/> </p> <ul> <li>The deadline for Summer EPFL 2022 was 1 December, 2021.</li> <li>One needs to give following documents: <ul> <li>CV</li> <li>Official Transcript</li> <li>Letter of Motivation</li> <li>professor preference (Optional But recommended)</li> </ul> </li> <li>Note LORs are not required in the Summer EPFL Program</li> </ul> <h2 id="post-application">Post Application:</h2> <p>Once the Application is done, most people start hearing about interviews for labs in between end december to mid jan. You could send a mail to prof and try communicating with phd docs for your application.I had mailed My professor and after few days I had received a Interview call from LAP Lab. <br/> The interview was a very shot call, a just about duration of 20 minutes. In which we discuss my past research projects, few FPGA related questions and later after a day I got to know I was selected as a Intern in Summer EPFL for LAP LAB.</p> <h2 id="visa-accommodation-and-others">Visa, Accommodation and Others:</h2> <ul> <li>First of all professors will introduce you to lab admin, who really helping me a lot with arranging Visa, accommodation and flight tickets.</li> <li>EPFL does reimburse Economy Flight tickets of students coming up in summer epfl, my lab admin had directly booked those tickets for me.</li> <li>For VISA process we need to wait for authority letter to come, which comes by march end in my case.</li> <li>For accommodation fmel is recommended.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="informative"/><category term="informative"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This summer I'm going to work with LAP LAB @ EPFL]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BeagleWire · Software for BeagleWire FPGA</title><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/beaglewire-software-for-beaglewire-fpga/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BeagleWire · Software for BeagleWire FPGA"/><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/beaglewire--software-for-beaglewire-fpga</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/beaglewire-software-for-beaglewire-fpga/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project Report for GSoC 2021 BeagleWire - FPGA development cape for the BeagleBone Black Table of Contents BeagleWire About Introduction Work Done ...]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Report of Verification Intern at SHAKTI</title><link href="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/shakti/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Report of Verification Intern at SHAKTI"/><published>2021-07-30T17:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-30T17:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/shakti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ombhilare999.github.io/blog/2021/shakti/"><![CDATA[<iframe src="/pdf/SHAKTI_REPORT.pdf" style="width:800px; height:1024px;" frameborder="0"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project"/><category term="project"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Detailed report of the work that I have done during SHAKTI internship]]></summary></entry></feed>